[
  {
    "type": "instructions",
    "note": "Each question is followed by four options lettered A to D. Find the correct option for each question"
  },
  {
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "1",
    "question": "The liberty of the individual in Ghanaian society can be curtailed when one",
    "answer": "A",
    "options": {
      "A": "speaks one's mind",
      "B": "refuses to vote",
      "C": "joins the opposition party",
      "D": "deserts national service"
    }
  },
  {
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "2",
    "question": "The extended family system in Ghanaian society has been undermined by",
    "answer": "A",
    "options": {
      "A": "formal education",
      "B": "lack of educational facilities",
      "C": "rural-urban migrations",
      "D": "influx of foreigners"
    }
  },{
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "3",
    "question": "The bringing together of all individuals in a nation based on common cultural traits is termed national",
    "answer": "C",
    "options": {
      "A": "alleigiance",
      "B": "identity",
      "C": "co-operation",
      "D": "pledge"
    }
  },
  {
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "4",
    "question": "The best way to ensure proper handling of currency notes is ",
    "answer": "C",
    "options": {
      "A": "encouraging more savings",
      "B": "providing wallets to workers",
      "C": "intensifying public education",
      "D": "printing of more currency notes"
    }
  },
  {
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "5",
    "question": "A society is said to be dynamic when its culture",
    "answer": "A",
    "options": {
      "A": "undergoes constant changes",
      "B": "varies from others",
      "C": "is preserved",
      "D": "is homogenous"
    }
  },
  {
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "6",
    "question": "A leader and a follower are inseperable because",
    "answer": "A",
    "options": {
      "A": "both are partners in the development process",
      "B": "they belong to the same religion",
      "C": "they have the same level of education",
      "D": "they have the same ethnic background"
    }
  },
  {
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "7",
    "question": "The greatest employer of labour in Ghana is the",
    "answer": "C",
    "options": {
      "A": "telecommunication industry.",
      "B": "banking industry.",
      "C": "public enterprise.",
      "D": "construction industry."
    }
  },{
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "8",
    "question": "The process of productions is said to be complete when goods",
    "answer": "B",
    "options": {
      "A": "reach the warehouse.",
      "B": "reach the final customer.",
      "C": "have been packaged.",
      "D": "are ready for distribution."
    }
  },
  {
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "9",
    "question": "Which of the following is not a cultural value of Ghana?",
    "answer": "A",
    "options": {
      "A": "Celibacy",
      "B": "Tolerance",
      "C": "Modesty",
      "D": "Symphathy"
    }
  },
  {
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "10",
    "question": "One result of a breakdown in constitutional rule is that, it leads to ",
    "answer": "D",
    "options": {
      "A": "illiteracy.",
      "B": "depletion of natural resources.",
      "C": "decrease in mining activities.",
      "D": "insecurity."
    }

  }
]
